# Glenn Kirk

1 Linen Lodge, Donaghcloney, Craigavon, BT66 7XG, United Kingdom +44(0)7702574447 • terids@gmail.com • Portfolio: http://terids.rf.gd Available from May 1st 2022

## **Background**

An experienced developer that has worked successfully, both as an individual and as part of large teams, in the Games Development and Virtual Production industries.

I have AAA exposure with Unreal Engine 4 and Unity 3D, including deep knowledge of the Unreal Engine DirectX 11 and 12 rendering pipeline.

#### **Patents**

2021 - Inventor (Part 1) Efficient graphical processing in 360-degree spherical space

2021 - Inventor (Part 2) Efficient graphical processing in 360-degree spherical space

## **Employment History**

Full employment history available upon request

## Graphics Engineer (Remote), OffWorldLive Ltd.

(April 2020 - May 2022)

- Co-Inventor of 2 patents for advanced 360 degree rendering and bloom techniques
- Researched, designed, and implemented an Unreal Engine livestreaming plugin which has since attained 30,000+ active users, with cinematic camera and 360 degree rendering functionality
  - > Worked with DirectX 11 and 12 to implement shared GPU textures between Unreal Engine and other local software
  - > Designed and implemented an authentication system within Unreal Engine to solve complex licencing requirements
  - ➤ Integrated libav (FFmpeg) C libraries to add real-time audio/video encoding and RTMP streaming from within Unreal engine
  - > Implemented a telemetry system to gather information on how users interact with the plugin
- Designed and implemented a WPF automation tool which receives commands over websockets to remotely control Unreal Engine and OBS Studio streaming
- Carried out profiling and optimisation of code, graphics, and networking per project as required
- Worked closely with external Virtual Production clients to implement custom level and gameplay features in C++ and Blueprints

### **Freelance VR Programmer (Remote)**

(May 2018 – April 2020)

- Genres worked on included a 2D platformer, VR astronaut first-person puzzle, and multiplayer match 3 game
- Working with Unreal Engine 4, Unity3D, and Godot game engines
- Gameplay and graphics programming for a number of clients

### Project Lead / VR Programmer / Designer (Remote, Contract), Holonautic

(*November 2018 – February 2019*)

- Planned and executed the development of a new VR project while leading a small team to meet target deadlines and goals
- Designed the gameplay, levels, and features
- Gameplay and graphics programming in VR for Unity 3D

### Placement Programmer, <u>Sumo Digital Ltd.</u>

(May 2016 – August 2017)

- ❖ Developed a AAA console title from prototype to green-light using Unity3D and Unreal Engine 4.
- Implemented a volume-based water physics system, compatible with any physics object in the game
- Worked with the art team to implement various particle effects and animations, such as firing turrets, water ripples and spray, and collectable items
- Worked with the audio team to implement different gameplay and menu audio effects using the WWISE platform
- Implemented camera positioning, movement, and FOV adjustments for player custom-made vehicles
- Implemented a pause menu system for game options and debug settings for development
- Designed and implemented a dialogue system using Excel and imported to the game using VB.Net and JSON, allowing designers to dynamically edit dialogue outside of the game engine

#### **Awards**

2017 Part 1 winner; Part 2 winner (And previous years 2016, 2015)
IBM Master the Mainframe

School Prize for Best Overall Performance in the First Year in Computing University of Central Lancashire

# **Key Skills**

2015

Languages	C++, C#, HLSL, GLSL, Cg, Lua, Java, C, Zig, VB.Net, HTML, JavaScript
Software	Unreal Engine, Unity 3D, Vulkan, DirectX 11/12, OpenGL, Perforce, Plastic SCM, Git